准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
强人宝宝
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜指导
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
马上就能好兴奋  烤架上面煎肉饼
Soon I will get a thrill, cooking patties on my grill
蟹堡王
蟹堡王因海胆暂停营业
入口
"Krusty Krab closed on account of urchins"?
往门缝塞钱随意
谢谢合作   蟹老板
我一定是在做噩梦
I must be in a nightmare
这不是噩梦  海绵宝宝
It's no nightmare, SpongeBob
蟹堡王要暂停营业一星期
I'm closing the old girl up for a week
把海胆除干净
to get rid of those prickly pests
并且我有灭海胆公司的优惠券
Plus, I had a coupon for Urchin B-Gone
我会有什么下场
What will become of me?
我一整个星期得干什么
What am I gonna do for a whole week?
你别急  小子
Slow your roll, Boy-o
我把你租给别人家的店上一星期的班
I've rented you out
to a different establishment for the week
这样这一周就还能有收入
so is not to disrupt me incomin' monies
好啊
Oh, boy
打临时工一听就很刺激
A temporary job sounds so adventurous
章鱼哥也一起吗
Is Squidward coming too?
他不来  我让他去搞文娱业了
Nope, I got him a job in the entertainment industry
总比跟海绵宝宝上班强
Still better than working with SpongeBob
我要去哪上班  蟹老板
Where will I be working, Mr. Krabs?
你要在强人俱乐部这边上班
You'll be working right here at The Salty Spitoon
强人俱乐部
不用了
No, thanks
太强人的地方我遭不住
That place is too tough for me
上班用不着当强人
You don't have to be tough to work here
看着像强人就行了
You just gotta look tough
好了
There
现在你样子就像个强人了
Now you look like a tough guy
我感觉不强  蟹老板
I don't feel tough, Mr. Krabs
等你进去了
Now when you go in there
就走到最大的客人面前
go up to the biggest customer
正视他的眼睛
look him squarely in the eye
让他知道你对人家的感受
And let him know exactly what you think of him
没问题  蟹老板
No problem, Mr. K
我最会正视了
I'm great at looking squarely
别搞笑了  小子
No funny business, Boy-o
我要向你说出我对你的感受
I'm gonna tell you exactly what I think of you
你的浅蓝眼睛最漂亮了
You have got the most beautiful baby blue eyes
谢谢
Thanks
从我妈那儿遗传下来的
I got 'em from me mother
蓝眼睛
Blue eyes?
众所周知我绿眼睛才最漂亮
Everybody knows my green eyes are the most beautiful
是吗
Oh, yeah?
是啊
Yeah
你一定就是海绵宝宝了
You must be SpongeBob
欢迎来到强人俱乐部
Welcome to The Salty Spitoon
我是这里的老板
I'm the owner of this joint
这就表示你现在要给我干活
That means youse works for me now
我的新老板
My new boss
很高兴认识
So nice to meet--
烤架在这
Here's the grill
锅铲在这
Here's the spatoola
快点把吃的做出来
Now make with the grub
好奇问一下
Just out of curiosity
你家上一任厨师怎么了
what happened to your last fry cook?
那是我们每月最佳员工墙
That's our employee of the month wall
每月最佳员工
不好好干活  下一张照片就挂你
Your photo is gonna be next if you don't get to work
别怕  海绵宝宝
Don't worry, SpongeBob
就跟在蟹堡王工作差不多
It'll be just like working at the Krusty Krab
蟹黄堡多做点哦  兄弟
Keep those patties comin', pal
我爱你
I love you
来份撒满钉子的砖块  多加机油
Gimme a brick covered in nails with extra motor oil
芝 麻
贝 果
糖 浆
这什么垃圾
What is this garbage?
我要的是撒满钉子的砖块
I asked for a brick covered with nails
我还以为是点餐黑话
I thought that was just diner lingo
抱歉
Sorry
撒满钉子的砖块  多加机油
Brick covered with nails, extra motor oil
很有强人俱乐部的范
Salty Spitoon style
这三明治就是强
Now that's a tough sandwich
砖块好嫩  钉子烤得好熟
The brick is so tender, and the nails are roasted
还有好几单要做  海绵宝宝
Got some more orders for you, SpongeBob
72份撒满机油的砖块马上就来
72 bricks covered in motor oil coming right up
真想不到
Whaddaya know?
大伙有什么意见
Whaddaya say, gang?
是火爆泡芙
It's Puff the Tuff
火爆泡芙
Puff the Tuff?
胖冬瓜
来份脏玻璃杯包碎玻璃高脚杯
Gimme a tall glass of broken glass in a dirty glass
那笑声
That laugh
不
No
不可能是他
It can't be him
谁点了炸弹烧烤
Who ordered the bomb-becue?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
那位是泡芙老师吗
Was that Mrs. Puff?
等一下
Wait a second
为什么火爆泡芙会怕你
Why is Puff the Tuff afraid of you?
她可能没认出我现在是个强人
She probably didn't recognize me now that I'm a tough guy
鞋带松了
My shoelace is untied
安全第一
Safety first
新来的那个小厨子还挺强
That new little cook seems pretty tough
是吗
Oh, yeah?
来看看他有多强
Let's see how tough he is
强人大考验开始
Let the trials of toughness begin
机械海公牛
Mechanical Sea-bull
小可怜
Poor thing
别人老是骑你  估计让你特别烦
You're probably tired of people riding you all the time
休息一下  骑我吧
Take a break and ride me
打水泥袋
Punching bag
打得好  海绵宝宝
Nice punch, SpongeBob
体毛力量
Body hair strength
我用下我黑心面
I'll just use my abrasive side
我宣布强人俱乐部里最强的人
I declare the toughest guy at The Salty Spitoon
就是海绵宝宝
Is SpongeBob SquarePants
作为我们的强人领导
As our tough guy leader
你有资格可以做任何事
you have the power to do whatever you want
强人章程
这样的话  我想给这里来点狂野的
Well, in that case, I've got a few wild ideas for this place
一天后
强人俱乐部
好了  各位
All right, guys
准备进裤头村最强人的地方打群架
Prepare to rumble
in the toughest place in Bikini Bottom
强人俱乐部
儿童乐园
对  不不不不
Yeah, no, no, no, no
就是这里没错
This is the right place
这里怎么回事
What's going on in here?
我要找这里的老板谈话
I demand to speak to whoever's in charge
欢迎光临  陌生人
Welcome, stranger
为什么来谈话的是个奶酪
Why is the cheese talking to me?
你不是要找强人领导谈话吗
You asked to speak with the tough leader?
不对  说真的
No, no, really
谁让这家伙进来的
who let this guy in here?
看得出来你对全新室内装饰赞赏有加
I see you're admiring the new décor
快告诉他装饰得怎么样
Tell him how it is, lad
我马上再做个更好的
I'll do him one better
怎么回事
What's happening?
欢迎大家前来弱人俱乐部
Come one and come all to The Softy Spitoon
弱人俱乐部
Softy Spitoon
有不少杯子蛋糕还有气球
Where all of our cupcakes come with a balloon
弱人俱乐部
Softy Spitoon
如果亲亲抱抱是你的愿望
If you like head kisses and cuddly hugs
弱人俱乐部
Softy Spitoon
那就举起牛奶  装进爱妈妈杯
And raise up your milk with "I heart Mom" mugs
我爱妈妈
弱人俱乐部
Softy Spitoon
准备
Ready?
弱人
Softy
够了
Enough
你们表现得跟弱小孩一样
You're acting like a bunch of weenies
香 肠
香肠
Weenies?
我们有的是  大家抢着要
We have those, and they are to die for
要不要加点新鲜腌料增添风味
A dab of freshly pickled relish, perhaps?
要哭就别来弱人
There ain't no cryin' in The Softy--
我是说强人俱乐部
I mean The Salty Spitoon
现在就这样了  毛毛
Well, there is now, buttercup
不喜欢就给我走
And if you don't like it, you can hike it
是吗
Oh, yeah?
是啊
Yeah
来看看海绵宝宝什么情况
Well, let's see how SpongeBob is doing
一定会特别好
This oughta be good
老螃蟹  你来干什么
Krabs, what are you doin' here?
一周时间还没到
The week ain't up yet
海绵宝宝没给你们惹麻烦吗
SpongeBob isn't giving you a problem?
麻烦
Problem?
没有  他是这里的舞会女王
Nah, he's the belle of the ball
其实吧  客人都特别喜欢他
In fact, the customers like him so much
我要永远把他留下来
I'm gonna keep him on permanently
不可以留下来
You can't do that
他现在就得跟我回去
He's coming back with me right now
是吗
Oh, yeah?
是啊
Yeah
我来带你回去  蟹老板
I better take you home, Mr. Krabs
这地方太强  你遭不住
This place is much too tough for you
你可能会受伤的  知道不
You might get hurt, see?
再见了  弱人俱乐部
Fare thee well, you old Softy Spitoon
我们会永远
We'll always have
所有人
Hey, everybody
那家伙绑走了我们领导
That guy is kidnapping our leader
弱人俱乐部
Softy Spitoon
弱人
Softy
俱乐部
Spitoon
年度最佳员工
凯伦照顾点点
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
好了  痞老板
All right, Plankton
我把12件换洗内裤装你行李箱了
I managed to fit
12 changes of underwear in your suitcase
装这么多外出够用吗
Will that be enough for the trip?
我要外出三天时间  凯伦
I'm gonna be gone for three days, Karen
没错  可以够用
so yeah, that should cover it
没错  点点
That's right, Spot
老爸要去贝壳城
Daddy has to go
参加一年一度的末日装备博览会
to the annual Doomsday Device Expo in Shell City
帮你找个终极邪恶道具
He's gonna find you an instrument of ultimate evil
会好好找的
Yes, he is
你放心  点点
Don't worry, boy
我给老妈留了不少说明
I left lots of instructions for Mommy
让她知道我外出的时候要怎么照顾你
so she knows exactly how to care for you while I'm gone
我的小家伙需要不少爱
My wittle man just needs wots of extra wove
要是有什么三长两短
and I would destroy the whole world
我就要毁灭全世界
if anything happened to him
你出租船到了
Your taxi's here
出租船
走吧  谢尔顿
Off you go, Sheldon
再见  凯伦
So long, Karen
再见  点点
Bye, Spotty
再见  痞老板
Bye, Plankton
一路顺风
Have a nice trip
看来只剩下你和我了  点点
Looks like it's just you and me, Spot
点点
Spot?
痞老板的说明
Plankton's instructions
点点  坏变形虫
Spot, bad amoeba
痞老板的小说明哪里用得上
Who needs Plankton's little notes?
我这精密的AI
A sophisticated AI like myself
照顾简简单单的有机生物可不成问题
should have no problem with a simple organic being
只要来点基本的分析
All he needs is a basic analysis
分析中
不行
No
我还没把你分析完
I'm not done analyzing you
厨房
点点
Spot
快跟上
Heel, boy
跟上
Heel
点点本来就该这样吗
Is he supposed to do that?
可能充点气就可以了
Maybe he needs a little pumping up
好了  点点
There you go, Spot
我害点点死了
I killed him
谁让你来的
Who sent you?
居然要来这
What do you know?
嗨  凯伦
Hi, Karen
小蜗要跟点点玩一阵子  记得吗
Gary has a playdate with Spot, remember?
跟点点玩啊
With Spot, huh?
那个嘛
Well, uh, the thing is
点点今天玩不了  因为点点
Spot can't play today because he's, uh--
很
he--
忙
busy
点点特别忙
He's busy
点点
He's, uh
忙着要
busy being, um
碎成渣还溅得到处都是
All over the place in bits and pieces
因为我害点点炸了
because I exploded him
点点是这样的
Yeah, that's Spot all right
点点  过来海绵宝宝这里
Spot, come to SpongeBob
你是怎么修复好点点的
How did you figure that out?
点点跟小蜗玩都会这样子
This happens all the time when he plays with Gary
我承认  在痞老板外出期间照顾点点
I admit, looking after Spot while Plankton is gone
比我想的还要难搞
is proving trickier than I thought
点点大概得来消耗一点能量
Maybe he needs to burn off some energy?
你怎么会这么壮
How are you so strong?
点点  看你捣的乱
Spot, look at this mess
快点  点点
Come on, Spot
不想跟小蜗一样乖吗
Don't you want to be a good boy like Gary?
点点  不要
Spot, no
不乖
Bad boy
鼻子上的应该不是我的甜甜圈
I nose this ain't my donut
点点跑太快了
He's too fast
情况还能糟到哪里去
How can this get any worse?
这里是凯伦的脑袋  请问你要找谁
Karen's head, how may I direct your call?
好
Yes
我可以找凯伦吗
May I talk to Karen?
等一下
Wait a minute
你是谁
Who is this?
是我
That was me
在发声音  现在我要来问你了
Throwing my voice, and now it's you
末日博览会怎么样了
How's the Doomsday Expo?
末日装备博览会
圆满结束了
It's over
我要早早回家
I'm coming home early
你要什么
You're what?
我都买了
But I bought
我能找到的最邪恶的统治世界装备
the most evil world-conquering device I could find
总之点点现在怎么样了
Anyway, how's my little Spot?
让点点接电话
Put him on the phone
我好想念点点的声音
I miss his voice
让点点接电话
Put Spot on the phone?
这部电话
This phone?
我的小家伙还在
There's my wittle man
一听就知道老妈对你呵护有加
Sounds like Mommy is taking good care of you
有个白痴把这个小行李箱
Some idiot left this tiny suitcase
落在明火旁边
next to an open flame
完了
Oh, no
该走了
Gotta go
趁痞老板还没回来  赶紧回去
Let's get back before Plankton comes home
小蜗
Hey, Gary
上班感觉怎么样
How was your shift?
怎么了
What's wrong?
你海霸糊碰都没碰
You haven't touched your chum
不用了
No, thank you
我不吃海霸糊
I don't really eat chum
对  我也不吃
Yep, me neither
凯伦
Karen?
你喂点点了没
Have you fed Spot yet?
没  点点不会从电池消耗能量吗
No, does he not consume power from his battery?
不会
No
点点要消耗别的东西
He consumes other stuff
你还饿吗
Are you still hungry?
好  要不要来吃
Okay, how 'bout a nice, um
纸巾盒
a napkin dispenser?
点点居然什么都能吃
Spot'll eat anything, huh?
一顿大餐之后
不能再吃了  点点
No more, Spot
你就快把咱家都吃穷了
You literally just ate us out of house and home
好  你还饿吗
Fine, you're still hungry?
你需要的所有食物我全都给你
I'll give you all the nourishment you'll ever need
来  我合成了永久营养药丸
Here, I synthesized a perpetual nutrient pill
可以不停把你喂饱
It'll keep feeding you so you'll be full
喂一辈子
Forever
凯伦
Hey, Karen?
点点长大算是正常现象吗
Is he supposed to be getting bigger?
这种情况我没计算过
That was not in my calculations
等会儿会不长的吧
It's gonna stop soon?
会吧
Right?
跟你说吧  海绵宝宝
Well, you see, SpongeBob
让药丸效力停止的程序我没写
I didn't program the pill to stop
完全没
Ever
我得多加小心对待你了
I gotta be careful with you
只要做错一步
One wrong move
你就会把整座海洋全炸飞
and you'll blow the whole ocean sky-high
美好时光不长久
The good times never last
凯伦
Karen
我便签没写要让点点变大的说明
None of my sticky notes
said to turn Spot into a behemoth
本来不会有这种事
Well, this wouldn't have happened
还不是你没把点点训练好
if you had trained him properly
我特别忙
I'm a busy man
你就该按我的说明来做
You should've been following my instructions
不好意思
Excuse me?
我可是你的电脑老婆  不是电脑女仆
I am your computer wife, not your computer maid
键盘整天让人敲  还得做牛做马
I slave all day over a hot keyboard--
所以都是我的错了
So everything is my fault
对于你  一切都是一和零
It's all ones and zeroes with you, honey
怕是你故意要让点点比我还要大
You probably made Spot bigger than me on purpose
让我觉得自己很渺小
To make me feel small
点点
Spot?
你全身就属你嘴巴最大
Your mouth is the biggest part of you--
所有跟你有关的东西都特小
Everything about you is small
我的心胸特宽广
My heart is big
我就不应该将就着你
I should not have settled
快看
Look
点点
Spot
好像要分裂了
I think he's dividing
点点不喜欢看老爸老妈吵架
He doesn't like it when Mommy and Daddy fight
快点过来
Come on, boy
来老爸这边
Come to Papa
来爸爸这边
Come to Daddy
快点过来
Come on, boy
快点
Come on
点点
Spot
看着这对可爱小脸蛋  我可气不起来
I can't stay mad at these cute little faces
我还是有点气
Well, I'm still a little mad